2 34
[00]Immigration
[01]New citizens won't come if your colony haven't got enough housing.
[02]Farming
[03]Upgrading your farm into hydroponics will stabilize its production, make it environment-independent and will no more consume island lifepower.
[04]Energy crystals
[05]You can transform your energy crystals into city energy - just select an energy capacitor and press the small plus icon. Every crystal adds 1000 energy points.
[06]Stream generator
[07]The Stream Generator power output depends both on wind power and on positioning. Try to build them as high as possible. Also you shouldn't rely only on Stream power - always have a reserve fuel generators and enough power capacitors.
[08]Trade docks
[09]Dock's trade volume depends on its workers count at the operation moment. If dock have no workers, no trade operations will take place! Also every docked ships being serviced pays a small fee.
[10]Settlement centers
[11]Settlement centers construct buildings automatically if needed, until reaches its limit. You can also construct buildings manually and exceed that limit. Centers limit based on its level, higher tiers unlock bigger buildings. Settlement center won't construct new houses if energy supply is zero or negative.
[12]Overflow
[13]If colony's storage is overflow some resources will be stored outside. To return them use the GATHER command on the surface. Also you can build resource blocks if you have more than 4096 of it.
[14]Gears
[15]A number near a hammer icon on colony's info panel displays gears level. It decreases with time and consumes by factories, farms and worksites activities. Set this value back and even increase it is workshop's business.
[16]Ores enrichment
[17]Try to construct Ore Enricher as soon as possible, otherwise you will dig tons of rock in search of metal ores. It recycles both stone and dirt. 
[18]Birth rate
[19]If your colony have a clinic, your citizens birthrate will raise from zero. You can also correct birthrate in the clinics control window.
[20]Psychic affection
[21]Psychokinetic generator decrease colony happiness, and moreover its workers sometimes disappears! Dont forget to free its workers if it is not needed anymore.
[22]Food reserves
[23]A carrot-indicator at the left upper corner of the screen displays stored food to month consumption ratio. Being invisible means you have more than one month volume.
[24]Total productivity value
[25]All your attemps to increase your factories production may be nullified if your colonists morale is too low. Always monitor housing and hospitals situation and watch for negative effects. 
[26]Free positioning
[27]You can anchor some building on side and down block's planes. However, building may be destructed if its basement has been removed.
[28]Quests
[29]Completing quests is an easy way to collect more energy crystal. Some quest is repeating over time.
[30]Exploring
[31]Use the "Rest" button if your crew is out of stamina to replenish up to 50%. Every such action consumes 1 supply crate. Replenished value depends on crew level.
[32]Progression
[33]Every succesfully completed challenge gives crew experience points. Gained enough points crew will get a new level, so you can distribute a new point to crew's stats.
